Amrith Setlur

■ asetlur@andrew.cmu.edu | • ars22 | • @setlur_amrith | ► Amrith Setlur

Research Overview.

My research broadly focuses on using theoretical foundations of machine learning for trustworthy machine learning, specifically in the context of large pretrained models. This involves understanding efficient learning algorithms that guarantee robustness to distribution shifts, uncertainty quantification, algorithmic fairness and privacy preservation for foundation models.

Education _

Carnegie Mellon University PhD in Machine Learning

Pittsburgh, PA

Jan 2022 - Present

CGPA: 4.05/4.0 ADVISOR: PROF. VIRGINIA SMITH

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

M.S. in Language Technologies

Aug 2019 - May 2021

CGPA: 4.12/4.0 Advisors: Prof. Barnabás Póczos and Prof. Alan W Black

National Institute of Technology (President's Gold Medal)

Trichy, India

B.S. (Honors) in Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA: 9.91/10.0; Institute Rank: 1

Aug 2013 - May 2017

Selected Publications¹.

Deep Neural Networks Tend To Extrapolate Predictably

Katie Kang, Amrith Setlur, Claire Tomlin, Sergey Levine; ICLR 2024 [PDF]

Project and Probe: Sample-Efficient Domain Adaptation by Interpolating Orthogonal Features

Annie S. Chen*, Yoonho Lee*, Amrith Setlur, Sergey Levine, Chelsea Finn; ICLR 2024 (Spotlight) [PDF]

Complementary Benefits of Contrastive Learning and Self-Training Under Distribution Shift

Saurabh Garg*, Amrith Setlur*, Zachary Lipton, Sivaraman Balakrishnan, Virginia Smith, Aditi Raghunathan; NeurIPS 2023 [PDF]

Multitask Learning Can Improve Worst-Group Outcomes

Atharva Kulkarni, Lucio Dery, Amrith Setlur, Aditi Raghunathan, Ameet Talwalkar, Graham Neubig; TMLR 2023 [PDF]

Contextual Reliability: When Different Features Matter in Different Contexts

Gaurav Ghosal*, Amrith Setlur*, Daniel Brown, Anca Dragan, Aditi Raghunathan; ICML 2023 [PDF]

Bitrate-Constrained DRO: Beyond Worst Case Robustness To Unknown Group Shifts

Amrith Setlur, Don Dennis, Benjamin Eysenbach, Aditi Raghunathan, Chelsea Finn, Virginia Smith, Sergey Levine; ICLR 2023 [PDF]

Leveraging Public Representations for Provably Private Transfer Learning

Pratiksha Thaker, Amrith Setlur, Virginia Smith, Zhiwei Steven Wu; TPDP 2023 [PDF]

Adversarial Unlearning: Reducing Confidence Along Adversarial Directions

Amrith Setlur, Benjamin Eysenbach, Virginia Smith, Sergey Levine; NeurIPS 2022 [PDF]

Two Sides of Meta-Learning Evaluation: In vs. Out of Distribution

Amrith Setlur*, Oscar Li*, Virginia Smith; NeurIPS 2021 [PDF]

Explaining The Efficacy of Counterfactually Augmented Data

Divyansh Kaushik, Amrith Setlur, Eduard Hovy, Zachary C. Lipton; ICLR 2021 [PDF]

Nonlinear Independent Subspace Analysis with Auxiliary Variables for Learning Speech Representations

Amrith Setlur, Barnábas Poczós, Alan W Black; Interspeech 2020 (Best Student Paper Finalist) [PDF]

Politeness Transfer: A Tag and Generate Approach

Aman Madaan*, Amrith Setlur*, Tanmay Parekh*, Barnabás Póczos, Graham Neubig, Yiming Yang, Ruslan Salakhutdinov, Alan W Black, Shrimai Prabhumoye; ACL 2020 [PDF]

An efficient fault tolerant workflow scheduling approach using replication heuristics and checkpointing in the cloud Amrith Setlur, S. Jaya Nirmala, Har Simrat Singh, Sudhanshu Khoriya; JPDC 2020 [PDF]

¹The * mark denotes equal contribution. Please see this page for the complete list.

Industry Experience

Apple Inc. (Hosted by Kunal Talwar & Vitaly Feldman)

Cupertino, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST INTERN May 2023 - Aug 2023

Worked on the problem of private and personalized histogram estimation in a federated setting. The main goal was to delineate the benefits of collaboration beyond learning a global model that is finetuned/personalized for each user. We use techniques from Good-Turing estimation and clustering to learn personalized histograms in a provably private way that also yields practical gains on real world data.

Amazon Research Bengaluru, IND

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Aug 2017 - May 2019

As part of the Ad Placement Optimization team, worked on prediction problems like advertiser claim detection and in the online setting on contextual product recommendations. Developed ML pipelines to match products for the "Frequently Bought Together" widget leading to a 0.4% improvement in click-through rate, for Sponsored Ads on Amazon.com.

Notable Accolades

- Academic: Recipient of three consecutive Institute Medals for the years 2014–15, 2015–16, 2016–17; President of India Gold Medal for securing the highest CGPA (9.91) across all departments; and the RECAL Alumni Award for "Best Academic Performance" and highest GPA in Computer Science Department.
- Scholarships and awards: Graduate Research Fellowship covering Tuition + Stipend from 2019-2021. Secured All India Rank 196 at JEE Mains Examination (AIEEE) 2013 and as a result received the AIEEE Merit Scholarship from HRD Ministry, Government of India (INR 140,000). CEDI TATA Industrial Grant of INR 40,000 for Most Innovative Undergraduate Thesis on extractive text-summarization. Best poster award at the LTI Student Research Symposium 2019.
- **ACM ICPC:** Represented the college at the ACM ICPC Regionals 2014 (Team Leader) and 2015 (Coach). Secured 1st positions at the Delta Algothon and the Algorithmic Coding Triathlon (Vortex) with 5000+ participants across the nation.
- IASc Research Fellowship: Proposed and implemented a polynomial time algorithm for K-median with outliers using two dimensional local search heuristics, specifically for large clusters (report). Advisor: Prof. Naveen Garg, IIT Delhi.

Relevant Coursework

- **Graduate Courses:** 36709 Advanced Statistical Theory (A), 10716 Advanced Machine Learning Theory and Methods (A+), 10725 Convex Optimization (A+), 10708 Probabilistic Graphical Models (A+), 10701 Machine Learning (PhD) (A+), 11731 Machine Translation (A+), 11747 Neural Networks for NLP (A+), 11777 Multimodal Machine Learning (A).
- Undergraduate Courses: MA101 Advanced Calculus (A+), MA102 Graduate Linear Algebra (A+), MA204 Probability Theory (A+), CS064 Artificial Intelligence & Expert Systems (A+), CS065 Natural Language Processing (A+), CS201 Data Structures & Algorithms (A+), CS212 Combinatorics & Graph Theory (A+), CS203 Discrete Structures (A+), MA304 Operations Research (A+).

Teaching.

- Teaching Assistant for 10725 Convex Optimization (Spring '23)
- Teaching Assistant for 10719 Federated and Collaborative Learning (Fall '23)

Service_

- Reviewer for NeurIPS (21', 22', 23'), ICML (22', 23'), ICLR (23', 24').
- Co-organized NeurIPS 2023 Workshop on Robustness of Few-shot and Zero-shot learning in Foundation Models.